For transportation and logistics, the most important thing is the tunnel.
When you pass through the tunnel, you will be happy in both directions.
There is a very important infrastructure where people and the city are connected and culture and economy are developing.
It is the top tunnel
Amazing
Seikan tunnel connects Honshu and Hokkaido
The tunnel is about to be built in the South of the century
The construction of Tokyo One Aqua Line has a big economic effect
A giant machine that that combines Japanese tunnel technology
It's amazing
Is this the one we used?
Exactly
Moreover, they also entered the aqua line's multi-area which they can't enter
It's a slide
And they investigate the front line of tunnel tunnel technology to open the future of Japan
Automated tunnel construction that solves serious human shortage
The more you dig, the more interesting it is
An hour to learn everything about tunnels
Bye bye in France!
Let's start the lesson.
Thank you for coming.
First of all, we have a report for you.
What is it? The winner of the 2023 application for the 73rd year of the year was our Momoiro Influenzet!
Wow!
It's a prize for the school festival.
So, is there any reward? Reward? What is it?
Applause!
The evaluation from the staff around me is also interesting.
I'm glad to see this program.
Yes!
Please tell me.
I can study properly.
I see.
Then, the theme this time is this.
Tunnel!
I've been on this show several times, but it's the first time we've seen a tunnel.
We've done the bridge, so we'll study the other tunnel.
We'll study the tunnel thoroughly.
In Japan, where three-quarters of the national territory is occupied by three countries, there are still many tunnels being built.
The number of tunnels connecting the railway and the road is more than 15,000.
It is the world's largest tunnel empire.
But it's definitely a tunnel to go anywhere.
If you want to go out for a while, you have to go through the tunnel.
I've been to a mountain in a sand place.
I was happy to see the mountain.
If you can make a tunnel, you can create a flow of people and things.
And the culture and economy will develop.
The impact is unexpected.
For example, in the past,
between Niigata and Tokyo,
you could only go to the mountains.
So most of the supplies to Niigata
were not delivered.
To develop Niigata, you need a tunnel.
So we made the Mikuni Tunnel.
We wanted to go from Tokyo to Niigata by car for the first time.
Thanks to this tunnel, a certain boom occurred in Japan.
What is it?
Boom?
Rice?
Rice.
Skiing boom.
There are many people in Tokyo who want in Tokyo, but they can't.
But they can go skiing in a car, so there are people who love skiing.
And then the ski boom happens, and at the same time, Niigata is getting more and more crowded with tourists.
For people in Tokyo and Niigata, if you go through the tunnel, both sides will be happy.
In 26 years later, the
The Niigata-Kan from Tokyo was shortened to 4 hours, and the weekend GERENDE was overflowing with couples.
In this way, the tunnel is a super important infrastructure that moves, transports, the transportation of water and electricity.
First of all, let's look at the very important example of a tunnel that has become a trigger for the world to become a tunnel nation.
The first mission is this.
This is it!
The main point of tunnel technology. Let's investigate the difficult construction of the century.
Japan has done a great construction.
Tamai-kun will be in charge of this mission.
I've been looking into it.
Are you ready?
Yes, of course.
Please take care of me.
This time, there are four missions prepared by Instructor Fujii.
The members in charge of member will report the results.
First, Tamai Kara, who showed off his guitar and piano skills at his solo concert.
Japan is known as the world's most powerful tunnel country.
When did the tunnel start being built?
Please take a look at this.
This is the number of road tunnels that have been built over a year.
This is where the tunnel construction has been increasing in earnest.
It's been increasing since around 1960.
It's increasing more and more.
At that time, Japan was under the influence of high-economic growth and the Olympics,
and infrastructure such as railways and highways rushed to construction.
At the same time, tunnel construction was also in full swing.
In the meantime, a major construction to amaze the world began.
That is here!
It is the Seikan tunnel.
This is the Seikan tunnel connecting Honshu and Hokkaido at the bottom of the sea.
It is called Aomori and Hakodate.
The tunnel length is 53.85 km.
It was the longest tunnel in the world at the time of opening.
It is the top tunnel with the longest tunnel in Japan, which is the longest tunnel in the world.
Have you ever been on this tunnel?
I have never been on the Shinkansen in Hokkaido, but I want to ride it.
I thought I could only ride it by plane.
This Shinkansen is a railway tunnel that runs through Shinkansen and Zairaisen.
Of course, it was effective in terms of tourism, but it had a greater impact than that.
Do you know anything?
Other than tourism?
Is it just a life-long logistics?
That's right!
The correct answer is this.
It had a great impact on the transportation of agricultural products.
In fact, 60% of the trains that passing through the Seikan tunnel are cargo trains
Many of the agricultural products shipped nationwide, including Hokkaido's onions, potatoes, and pumpkin, rice, and dairy products, are transported by this cargo train passing through the Seikan tunnel
Until then, the food was transported across Until then, they were transported by boat across the river.
Thanks to the Seikan tunnel,
they can deliver food at a cheap and fast rate.
Fresh agricultural products are now delivered to the table of the whole country.
I feel like it's going to be delicious just because it's Hokkaido.
I want to go to the Guri-San-Ten.
The image was created thanks to this tunnel.
The construction of the Seikan tunnel was a challenge that could be said to be reckless in the technology at the time.
What was the plan?
The plan was to dig 23km under the sea. Digging from Aomori and Hokkaido.
And then, they were planning to penetrate 240m underground.
They were going to gather here?
Yes, they were.
They were waiting for the right time.
They were going to dig sand and sand.
They were going to touch the snow. It was difficult to do that. It's a meeting place. We dug the tunnel with our friends and we tested it with a snowmobile.
It was difficult to do it with this size.
Sometimes we couldn't meet.
There was a seabed tunnel in Japan, but this size was the first in the world.
We had to think about what it would work or not.
So, we decided to dig two more tunnels, in addition to the main one.
We decided to dig three tunnels in total.
That's a lot of work.
We dug two more tunnels to dig one tunnel.
Why?
But it's not useless, right?
Yes, it's all necessary.
The first thing to dig is called the forward-looking tunnel.
This is a small tunnel for investigation to check the condition of the seabed at the bottom.
Next, the work tunnel is dug.
It is a tunnel for transportation that carries workers and equipment from the ground, and carries carved stones and sand.
And finally, the main tunnel that the railroad runs, Honko.
The three tunnels are connected by contact route.
Today, we have seen a lot of sandstone, but if you dig a little bit, it will collapse. That's right.
So, the more the number of sandstone, the more the risk.
To dig a world of unknown, called the seabed, three tunnels were needed.
3 tunnels were needed to get to the top
In order to achieve this difficult mission and to fight against the complicated seabed and spring water
we introduced the latest technology called the Three Species of Human Art
Here it is
A forward bowling that will prevent future dangers.
This is a ground-based intrusion that protects the intrusion of seawater.
Is there something in it?
I can't say because the clothes are different.
This is a blow-in concrete that hardens the tunnel in an instant.
This is in it.
When digging a tunnel, it is called a bowling survey to dig a thin hole and investigate the situation of the ground.
In the past, the ground was a few meters away, but this advanced boring was able to investigate up to 2000 meters away with the latest machine.
Next is the ground penetration.
Since the seikan tunnel digs the ground at the bottom, the seaw so the seawater enters the seabed through the crack in the rock.
Therefore, we introduced a new technology that injects special solution to the ground floor
and then digs it so that it does not collapse.
And finally, we used the blow-in concrete.
In the Seikan tunnel, it was important to quickly solidify the dug area
to prevent the water from dripping and the floor from collapsing, it was important to quickly solidify the dug area.
So, the concrete was directly blown into the inside of the 12th year since the construction began, a terrible accident happened.
What?
It was a water leak from a transport tunnel. 70 tons of water were leaked every minute.
The tunnel for transportation was flooded.
Water was also pushed into the main tunnel where the railroad runs.
Experienced workers were in trouble.
They tried to weaken the momentum of the water.
They piled up a bag of cement and saved time.
They closed the area where the water that had not been flooded yet.
And they managed to protect the tunnel.
That's amazing.
It's a life-saving experience.
They overcame the water leak that occurred many times.
There were many times like this.
March 1988, 24 years after the landing.
Finally, the Seikan tunnel was finally opened.
The national project, which was supported by 14 million workers, was successfully completed.
The completed Seikan tunnel, the main tunnel, and the main tunnel, of course, are active as railway tunnels, but there are two other tunnels.
In fact, this tunnel for investigation and the tunnel for transportation are also important after completion.
That's not all.
It's because we made it.
The role of the tunnel for transportation is this.
It is used for maintenance inspection. There are also facilities to inspect the Seikan tunnel, which runs on the Shinkansen and the Zainai Line, and an area for tourists to visit on a cable car.
It looks fun.
It's a place to see.
On the other hand, the tunnel is smaller than the other level and is used for research purposes.
Now, let's check the infrastructure!
What is it and what is it?
The 3m high and 4m wide tunnel for research.
What is the purpose of the tunnel after construction?
Here you go. To star? Toho?
Toho?
Oh, you mean walking?
Some people are walking.
But no one has walked in Aomori-kawa, Hokkaido.
It's very stoic.
I think it's necessary to have a hotel.
There is no rail on the railroad, so the car runs.
That's a good idea. But there are no rails, so the car can run.
It's not that easy.
Actually, you can't operate the tunnel without this.
There is something that can be taken out of the tunnel, but it's not by human power, is it?
No, it's not.
Air?
Oh, it's a So, what about the Tokyo Dome? The Tokyo Dome's... The air-conditioning system?
No, I mean, are they putting air in the system?
Yes, they are.
It's ventilation.
One of them is ventilation.
If the air is not ventilated, the oxygen will be gone.
The survey tunnel connected to the ground The tunnel for the investigation of the sea level is used as an air-flow system to ventilate the Seikan tunnel by the wind machine.
Yes, it is a seawater tunnel.
It's a seawater.
Water.
Is the water flowing?
Well, this. Oh, yes.
It's not a T.
It's a drain.
The correct answer is this.
The tunnel in the game is used for ventilation and drain.
Leader and Aerin's double correct answer.
You're right.
You're not strong. You're right. Correct! Ren, you are so strong!
Ren, please walk!
The tunnel is connected to the pump room inside the tunnel and acts as a duct to drain the water.
The underground water is still in the deepest part of the tunnel and is drained from the tunnel for investigation by the main power of the pump.
Behind the difficult construction of the Seikan Tunnel, which is essential for Japan's lifeline, there was a thorough plan, a revolutionary method, and the technical ability of the Shinkansen, there were detailed plans, revolutionary methods, and the workers' certain technical skills.
The Shinkansen tunnel, which has a great economic effect, connects Honshu and Hokkaido.
However, since Shinkansen and freight trains use the same tracks, there is also challenges that the Shinkansen cannot use its original speed.
So,
There is a concept of the second Shinkansen tunnel.
There are various ideas.
The idea is to run the cargo and pass the highway.
It's like a dream! Yes, it is.
Hokkaido is now only connected by rail,
and we can't transport trucks.
I see.
However, most of Japan's logistics is truck transportation,
so if this is connected by expressway,
it will be cheaper.
And people in Tokyo and all over the country
will be able to get Hokkaido products at the people in Tokyo and the rest of the country.
We can go there as soon as possible.
According to the Japan Project Industry Association,
the second Seikan tunnel will be built right next to the Seikan tunnel.
The annual cost of the project is estimated to be 8.78 billion yen per year.
But it's going forward.
There is such a discussion. The government still has a lot of money problems.
If you can make it, the future is like this.
If the Japanese people want this, the government will realize it.
It is important to know this.
We will interview young employees who are involved in the infrastructure.
We are YOUNG INFRASTRUCTURE.
This is Yurika Shoji, the second year of joining the company.
She is currently in charge of SAKITAMA BASHI, the second longest in Saitama prefecture, SAKITAMA bridge, is currently in charge.
She is involved in the construction of the bridge.
The standard of strength for earthquakes is changing.
We are strengthening the bridge to meet the standard.
She works hard every day to protect her safe life.
What is her goal?
I like research, so I want to be a doctor.
I think we need to know more about the woodwork in the field. I hope we can challenge the work related to the construction space.
Good luck, young Infra players!
Here is the next mission. Infra-senshi-tachi Next mission is this
Let's investigate Tokyo Bay Aqua Line, which has the best tunnel technology in Japan
Thank you
You all know Tokyo Bay Aqua Line
Momota will be in charge of this mission
Did you check it thoroughly?
I did. The one who investigated this mission is Momota who recently became not good at roller coaster.
Now, let's go to the highway connecting Chiba and Kanagawa prefecture, which is also the birthplace of you three.
Thank you.
Tokyo-1 Aqua Line.
Of course, as you can see from your tension, we have been through Aqua Line many times.
I was so excited when I was able to drive Aqua Line.
I was like, Aqua Line is running!
The total length of Aqua Line is 15.1km.
This is the 9.5km long Aqua tunnel.
It is the world's largest underground road tunnel. The total cost of the aqualine completed in 1997 was 1.5 trillion yen.
However, the effect was tremendous.
First of all, the distance.
For example, the distance from Han prefecture to Kisarazu.
It takes more than an hour to get to the Tokyo Bay.
It takes about 20 minutes to get to the Aqua Line.
It's about 1 third of the time.
I think Kisarazu is close.
It's a neighborhood.
It's easier to move around, so more people visit and come.
The tourism consumption in Shito Prefecture, which was created 20 years after the opening of the Aqua Line, is up to 45 billion yen.
Wow.
About one-third of the construction cost is covered by tourism alone.
That's what it is.
We also have a lot of money in sightseeing. We can get a lot of money from sightseeing. We can get a lot of money from sightseeing.
We can get a lot of money from sightseeing.
Kisarazu City, which has improved access to the city,
has increased its population year by year.
Since 1981,
something has been made for the first time in 33 years. something has been made for the first's been 33 years since the first thing was made.
It's an outlet.
It's a very out-let image.
It was made because the population increased.
It's a school.
A school?
Wow!
It's Tafai's!
It's here!
A strike!
Yay!
It's fast today. I! Strike! You're fast today!
Let me play with you for a bit.
Correct!
It's elementary school.
Because it's more convenient to travel to the city, the number of families has increased.
I don't hear that it's possible to go to elementary school in the neighborhood.
It's amazing.
It's often said that. That's amazing. It's like, the insect is gone.
Thanks to this aqua line, Kisarazu City has been sinking in the water, but only Kisarazu City has been growing.
Amazing!
The aqua line that we are familiar with is actually a Nankouji that took about 30 years to open, and it was called the Apollo Project of the Dome.
It was a challenge to collect all the know-how and cutting-edge technology and go to the unknown.
What was the tunnel technology in Japan?
Momoi Line, please.
Tokyo Bay Aqua Line Construction The construction of Tokyo Bay Aqua Line started in 1987.
Why was the construction so difficult?
The floor of Tokyo Bay was too soft.
The floor of the Aqua Line was too soft.
It was compared to a certain food.
Marshmallow? That's good. No, it's not. It's a as food. Marshmallow.
That's good.
That's not it.
It's a little softer.
Is it softer?
That's not it.
It's soft.
Mochi.
That's good.
You're a little scared.
What is it that collapses?
Tofu is different.
Miso.
Yes, seasoning.
It's close.
It's close. It's close.
It's getting closer.
Nuka.
Where's the nuka?
Nuka-zuke?
Nuka-zuke, nuka is a little hard.
It's more round and round.
It's already coming.
Mayonnaise.
Correct!
Anin loves mayonnaise.
I love it. I love mayonnaise.
As you can see, the mayonnaise is easy to break and the tunnel will collapse.
I decided to dig a deeper underground of the soft ground.
But the problem occurs here.
In Japan, the tunnel is often dug in the method called the Natomu-Kouho.
For example, what is the method?
First, open a hole in the wall with a gun and set a bomb there.
Bomb?
Yes.
It's a bomb! It's a bomb!
When you dig it out, you have to blow up concrete to prevent it from collapsing.
But if you use a bomb under the soft ground like mayonnaise, it will collapse with vibration no matter how much you reinforce it.
So, the first one adopted in the Japanese seabed tunnel was the shield machine.
I think I've seen it before.
Do you know that there is such a monument in the sea?
Do you know?
There is.
This one?
This one.
Is this the one you used?
That's right. This one! This one! Is this the one you were using? Exactly. This is the blade part called the cutter face that was actually on the tip of the shield machine that actually dug the Aqua Tunnel.
The diameter of this blade was about 14 meters, which was the world's largest blade at the time.
If we go there next time, everyone will say that we dug it with this.
Please take a look at how this huge shield machine dig a tunnel?
First, use a cutter with a tip and dig a 30mm hole at a speed of 30mm per minute.
If you leave it as it is, the ground will collapse, but here is the most advanced function.
At the same time as digging a tunnel, we will build a wall of concrete blocks on the spot so that the floor does not collapse.
Wow!
It does the work of digging and making that many workers have done so far at once.
Thanks to this, the efficiency of the work has increased, and the safety aspect has also improved significantly.
After that, I thought that I would just dig a while, but there was another big problem.
That is water pressure.
That's right. It's the sea.
For example, it's about the same as putting a 6kg dumbbell on the nail of a little finger.
It's hard.
It's going to be crushed.
It's going to be crushed Even if they continue digging with a shield machine, the floor will collapse due to water pressure
The concrete block will soon harden and the water and mud will flow into the big wall
Here is the question! When you start digging, the soft ground breaks down immediately.
To dig further with a shield machine,
there is a way to prevent mud and seawater from entering.
What is that method?
It is the construction of an aqua tunnel that digs under the soft ground like mayonnaise.
The process of building an aqua tunnel.
What is the way to protect the aqua tunnel from mud and sea water?
What is the method to harden the aqua tunnel?
There was a method before.
There was a method before. There was a method before. There was a method before. Yes, yes, yes. What does that mean? It means to cool down.
Oh, I see.
You can cool it down.
I learned something.
When we make a dam in Kurobe,
a lot of water comes out.
But in winter, the water freezes.
So we made a tunnel.
We made it artificial.
I see.
That's a great answer. Let's see the answer. I'll do it artificially. I see. You've been It's frozen. So, Tamai-san, Sasaki-san, and A-chan, you two are the correct answer.
A-chan, you're not in a good mood today.
But the correct answer is, you froze the board.
That's correct.
It's called the frozen method.
How?
Here's the mechanism.
First, insert several pipes into the ground and put a special liquid that has cooled down to minus 20 degrees.
Then, the pipes will cool down and the water contained in the ground will freeze.
With just one pipe, you can only make a small ice wall, but by combining them, a large ice wall is completed.
Even if you start digging with this, you don't have to worry about collapsing.
The shield machine will automatically install concrete blocks, so you can make a tunnel safely.
It's been thought a lot. The automation of this concrete block and the success of the thawing method were highly evaluated not only in Japan but also around the world.
For example, this Japanese tunnel technology was The world was also influenced by it.
The Tokyo One Aqua Line, which was called the Apollo Project of the desert.
It was a great step to develop tunnel technology.
Aqua tunnel made with such cutting-edge technology.
In fact, there are still amazing lot of secret to be found!
Next mission!
Let's investigate the Maruhi area of the Tokyo Bay Aqualine!
I want to know!
Is that okay?
Sasaki will be in charge of this mission!
Thank you!
This mission is about Sasaki's happiness is the happiest when eating her favorite dress, will investigate.
Tokyo Aqua Line was created by collecting Japanese tunnel technology.
Do you know that there are areas where people do not usually enter?
I don't know.
You don't need it.
Of course.
This time, we have entered a secret area in a tunnel 60 meters below sea level.
Momoiro Infra, set!
We are driving on the Aqua Line.
Let's go!
We will dive into the sea from here.
Do you remember this sign on the left side of the road?
Yes, I do.
It's the sign of emergency exit.
If you go straight, you'll see an emergency exit on the way to the underground tunnel.
I wonder what's going to happen next.
Will it continue to the ground?
When I opened the emergency exit,
I found something that was not above the ground but was going down.
Actually, it's a slide.
What is ahead?
It's a quiet space.
Where are we going?
We are going to see the next stop, Wakabayashi in East Japan.
This is an emergency exit for the public cars.
We used a shield machine to dig the Aqua Tunnel.
The section is circular as shown.
The upper side is the road and the lower side is the emergency exit.
Since it is a shield machine, it is a circular Aqua Tunnel. The upper side is the long-distance structure.
The water tunnel is located on the top and the water tunnel is located on the bottom.
If a fire occurs in the tunnel, the water tunnel is connected to the escape route.
The escape route has a slope of 300 meters.
It's safe.
There was also a mechanism device for this evacuation passage.
This is a wind-shrinkable wind-shrinkable air.
By blowing the wind, the air pressure is maintained at a high level, and smoke and fire from the airfield are not included.
It's a very important mechanism.
Air flows from high to low pressure.
Air pressure of evacuation passage is high.
It prevents fire and smoke from flowing.
Furthermore, There is another slope besides this.
Let's go there.
There is another slope. Let's go there.
The one we were guided to is right next to the slope we just came down. There is a slope that is thicker and straighter than the slope we just came down.
This slope is to return to the main station from this evacuation passage.
Oh, it's the one that goes up.
Now, let's check the infrastructure!
This slope is made in a straight line so that it can easily climb up the tunnel from the evacuation passage.
What was the purpose of this slope?
This slope is to go back to the tunnel from the evacuation passage.
What is the use of the slope that goes back to the tunnel from the passageway?
It's easy to climb, isn't it?
If people climb, they can use stairs.
That's true.
But it's kind of deep.
It's not a person.
It's like a fire extinguisher.
Tamari-san, you're close.
Fire extinguisher?
It's a fire extinguisher!
Wow!
That's fast!
Takagi-san hasn't said anything yet.
I'm thinking about it.
You're still figuring out the meaning of the question.
Let's see the answer.
First, please see this video
Amazing
The fire truck runs through the evacuation passage
Fire truck can also be on the train
Fire truck can be on the train at the bottom
When the train stops at the station, the firemen cannot reach the site.
From this evacuation passage, the firemen are brought here.
The firemen run up the slope and do fire activities.
The correct answer is the slope for firemen to do fire activities.
So, Mr. Amsan is correct again. Amazing!
I'm sorry.
I thought it was wrong, but I got it right.
It is designed to be wider than an evacuation slope so that firefighters can climb with their tanks.
It is also prepared for sliding.
I'm most interested in where the fire truck came from.
I didn't hear that.
Where does this fire truck come from?
This is the fire truck running on the evacuation passage.
Wow!
It's like an aqua line fire truck.
This is the artificial island and the sea firefly that floats in the center of the aqua line.
I love the sea firefly.
I love it.
There is a fire truck garage here.
You can get to the site by passing emergency passage to get to the site.
It's connected.
We are not only having fun, but we also have a role to play.
The fire station we saw earlier is smaller than the fire truck we usually see?
Compared to the fire truck that runs on a normal road, it is a little smaller.
This is a fire truck for emergency passageways.
It is a compact size that can pass through a 2.7m high and 3.6 meters wide. It is compact and can be used in the passageway.
It is open for 27 years.
There is no fire department yet.
It is maintained so that it can be used safely.
It was like this.
It is amazing to make a fire department with a
guess. That's right. It's amazing that they made it with the assumption of a possible accident.
This evacuation passage and fire truck can be seen by anyone who participates in the tour.
Tokyo Bay Aqua Line, which has accumulated tunnel technology, has a lot of ingen tricks to prevent accidents and disasters.
I think that it is convenient to use as a user because it can pass through tunnels.
However, it is dangerous if the system that can fire long tunnels is not properly maintained.
Such technology is also very advanced in Japan.
Interviewing young employees' passion for infrastructure.
Young infrastructure Z!
Minori Ushikubo, 6 years in ZENECON.
She is in charge of construction.
The construction company in charge of the water supply is
The construction company is responsible for the water supply of the river as a flood control for the Chakji River.
The Chakji River is a first-class river that flows through the northwestern part of Tokyo.
When typhoons and heavy rain come, the water and maintain the water supply area to prevent water pollution in the city.
When I see the construction work of the neighbors, I want to be a role model for female technicians who will continue to appear on the scene and become a role model for female technicians who will continue to increase.
Go for it, young Infra players!
The next mission is this.
Next mission is this. Let's investigate the front line of tunnel technology that opens the future of Japan.
Takagi-kun has been investigating this.
Thank you.
This mission is a survey by Takagi who asks people the problem of people working in the industry. In the past 10 years, more than 200,000 people have been reduced.
The entire industry has been in need of people due to the deterioration of age.
As it is, it may be impossible to create a tunnel that is indispensable for the convenience of people's lives.
Here is the method to eliminate the lack of people.
It is self-sufficient. So, we are now working on this to eliminate the lack of human resources.
It's automated.
We are developing a technology to automatically work so that even a small number of people can work safely and smoothly.
We are now entering the forefront of what kind of technology is automated the best. Momoiro Infra-Jet!
First, we are in Nassu-Shiobara City, Muchigi Prefecture.
What is this vast land?
It's a kamaboko-shaped facility.
This is a tunnel made for experiments. What is this? This is a kamaboko-shaped facility. This tunnel was made for experiments.
What is this?
What is going on here?
This is an iron structure called a shihoko.
In tunnel construction, the structure is supported by a structure called a square frame.
This is an important work that can not be allowed even a slight shift.
Therefore, it is necessary to make fine adjustments by hand and assemble it perfectly.
Usually, it is done by at least 5 people, but we developed a technique to break that common sense.
What?
A fully automatic high-end quadrupedal stand robot has appeared with a quadrupedal stand.
How powerful is it?
Start the automatic stand. Wow! and start the robot. The robot inputs the data from the design
and starts the work with one button.
The operator just sits down and the robot works.
And the automatic square light installation is complete.
It's really attached.
The work is completed in half the normal time.
Until now, only people who were used to working could operate the machine.
But now, even if a child presses a button,
they can stand up.
Anyone can do it.
Even young people,
even people who just started working, can do it.
We can solve the problems of lack of people.
In addition,
other revolutionary machines were also developed at this site.
The yellow shovel car that you often see running is a human.
Please be careful of the driver's seat.
It's a human.
Of course, this is not a
rare phenomenon.
It is running with a new automation technology called Tunnel Remorse.
Wow.
So how does it work?
It's guided by a small Prehab hut.
There is a driver who seems to be coming out to the game center.
It looks fun.
The previous shovel was remote controlled.
Cool!
It's also popular among pilots.
As you can see, the cockpit is shaking.
The cockpit is shaking.
The cockpit is in sync with the vibration of the gun and the cockpit fits the vibration.
This gives the driver the feeling that the gun is actually operating.
It's easy to do.
I think shaking is necessary.
It is easier to grasp the movement. By reproducing the shaking and tilt of the scene,
you can show delicate craftsmanship even in a remote place.
In fact, experiments to control the machine gun of the Totsugi
were also carried out from the Chinese region such as Hiroshima and Okayama.
You don't have to go.
And it is equipped with a function of maximizing this remote control.
One of the features of this remote control is that you can remote control any machine by selecting it here.
One?
This allows you to drive 7 types of aim to make the mountain tunnel unmanned,
and we can operate remotely only one machine.
If other machines are on the road,
it is impossible to make the tunnel completely unmanned.
We are developing with the intention of making all machines unmanned.
Amazing.
Next, we entered Ifufu-ken, Hirashi. Here, they are actually digging a mountain and developing technology.
This is a 2-boom automatic lock bolt.
This is the world's first robot that has been successfully automated.
It is a 2-boom lock bolt.
SU-BOOM Lock Bolt
Lock Bolt is a reinforcement material that is used to prevent collapse and deformation by hitting into the tunnel wall.
First, make a hole to put the bolt into the wall.
Insert the mortar into there.
Insert the bolt and fix it.
In the past, it was a hard work for 5 people.
However, this machine allows operators to work alone.
With this boom, they can do the work of opening hole, inserting mortals, and inserting bolts. He can do the work of five people with just one button.
He says that he succeeded in developing this automatic lock bolt machine because he was able to test it in the actual mountain.
There are six unit tasks in tunnel construction, and this lock bolt machine is one of them. In the future, we would like to optimize the overall cycle,
that is, improve the productivity.
Next, we came to Keio Technical University in Kawasaki City, Kanagawa Prefecture.
Here, universities and companies are jointly developing technology.
While students are also doing joint research, in the corner of the room
There is a small robot that is less than 1 meter long
What kind of work is it used for?
This robot is used to make gunpowder
Explosion needed to dig a tunnel.
Normally, a skilled worker will put a gunpowder on the wall by hand.
It's dangerous.
How does it work?
Please look at the picture.
A white robot is next to a blue robot, there is a white robot.
When the white robot starts to operate,
Wow, it's moving!
Look! The blue robot, which is not with anyone, starts to move with it.
Amazing!
By operating the robot while looking at the monitor,
it can perform the operation of filling the gunpowder remotely.
Wow, it's working.
The white robot you see moving
is a simple remote control.
This white remote control
is used to operate the blue robot.
Wow.
It's called the automatic chemical loading system.
With this, you can use the camera on the site
and operate remotely control the area.
The remote control technology is also very difficult.
However, the most important thing in the process of filling this gunpowder is...
Just putting the gunpowder there does not cause a shock to the ground.
To do this, you have to push the gunpowder into the back.
The work that is necessary is the condition of pushing the gunpowder into the hole That's why we had to push the gunpowder into the hole
This is the feeling of gunpowder
The explosion of the tunnel with multiple gunpowder in one hole
To make the tunnel explode efficiently, you need to fill the gunpowder with the best feeling
Now, let's move on to Infra 9!
To enable the gunpowder to be filled from a place where it cannot be seen,
there is a very advanced feature.
What is it?
What is the most advanced feature that allows you install a gunpowder in the distance?
The sound of the gunpowder is telling you the distance.
It's not a signal that love. You can't put it in three pieces.
That's true.
I put it in the distance and put it in the case.
It's not a sense of distance.
It's a feeling of touch.
It's a function of the touch. It's a function of the touch.
It's a function of the touch.
I thought it was a function of the touch.
Please see the correct answer.
Please look closely.
Really?
Please pay attention to the moment the blue robot hits.
Oh, that means it's transmitted to this machine.
When the blue robot hits, with a white robot, it bounced back. The power of the robot when it collided with something is also reproduced in the remote control.
It is a feeling that you are actually inserting a stick on the spot.
It is a great answer that you can feel it.
Tamai-san, you are right.
I'm scared.
I was like, what?
But you were right earlier.
The vibration is important.
This is a function called Real Haptics, which is used in the field of delicate work such as medical field.
Please see the work that can be crushed by normal remote control, you can crush the cup.
Amazing!
As you can see, it's very powerful.
Yes, it is.
This feeling is also...
Yes, you can feel the power.
You can take the cup gently without crushing the cup.
The tunnel works are applied to the real haptics that were originally developed at Keio University of Technology. By conveying the feeling of filling the gunpowder, it is possible to reduce the workstation where we can operate various robots from a workstation.
In order to eliminate the lack of people, the tunnel construction technology is advanced.
In the future, the future where tunnels can be built all by hand may come.
Amazing, Mr. Tamai, you are right all the way.
Wonderful. Finally. I feel like the gods are coming. Tamayamori-san, you got all the questions right. It's wonderful.
I feel like the gods are coming down.
The gods of the infrastructure.
Tunnels dig into the mountains.
Even if you dig a mountain, the enemy will collapse if you dig it.
There is a problem that many it will be sacrificed So the fact that we dug a lot of tunnels
is that Japanese technicians have accumulated technology
on top of many sacrifices for hundreds of years
I think it is very important to make various dreams come true
using this technology to make Japan develop further
and make use of this strength
The next theme of the Momoiro Infra Z is
City building!
Utsunomiya is now hot!
What is the plan to rebuild the region?
Furthermore,
A great recovery once in a century!
We will thoroughly discover Shibuya, which continues to evolve!
We will thoroughly discover Shibuya, which is evolving!
On June 2nd, Sunday, 11AM, on air! Look forward to it!
Momoiro Infra Z is broadcasted with the cooperation of the following partners.